<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Miscellaneous on </title>
    <link>https://example.com/misc/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Miscellaneous on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://example.com/misc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Encodings</title>
      <link>https://example.com/misc/encodings/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/misc/encodings/</guid>
      <description>Unicode Unicode is a Standard, not an Encoding Standard for consistent encoding, representation and handling
 Maintained by Unicode Consortium consists of more than 140&#39;000 graphic characters, 160 format characters covers more than 150 modern and historic scripts, multiple symbol sets and emojis  UTF-8 UTF-8 is a variable-width character encoding. Defined by the Unicode standard.
Base64 Base64 is a group of binary-to-text encoding schemes. Represents binary data in ASCII string format</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>nginx configuration</title>
      <link>https://example.com/misc/nginx/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/misc/nginx/</guid>
      <description>NGINX configuration NGINX is a web server which can also be used as a reverse proxy, load balancer, mail proxy and HTTP cache. The NGINX alias directive defines a replacement for the specified location. For example, with the following configuration:
location /app/ { alias /var/www/app/; } on request of /app/top.gif, the file /var/www/app/top.gif will be sent. But, if the location doesn&amp;rsquo;t ends with directory separator (i.e. /):
location /app { alias /var/www/app/; } on request of /app.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vim</title>
      <link>https://example.com/misc/vim/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/misc/vim/</guid>
      <description>#delete a word small w only considers letters big W also considers brackets c cuts and goes into insert mode afterwards d only cuts
caw, daw	cut word including space after it ciw, diw	cut word without space
ctrl-v	enter Visual block mode shift-I	go insert mode, change entire block
Command :&amp;gt;&amp;gt; and :&amp;lt;: shift two indents to the right / one to the left
Macros  Recording: press q followed by key you want to store the makro in, then do your thing, in the end, press q in normal mode again.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>